Inventory of the Charles Campbell Papers 1743-1896
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Family and Professional Papers (Box 2-17)
  - Letters, 1850-1859., 467 items. (Box 8-11)
    - Letters, 1859., 80 items. (Box-folder 11:80-159)
      - Henry Howe, Cincinnati to Cha[rle]s Campbell, Petersburg, 24 February 1859., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:108)
        Has had some difficulty with violations of the law because of the selling of his books without a license, but he does not expect to be prosecuted. Decries the high cost of obtaining licenses, which makes it impossible to sell books in Virginia. Hopes the law will be changed.
      - William Palmer, Richmond to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 25 February 1859., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 11:109)
        Palmer had destroyed manuscript of his History of Virginia. Navy during Revolution, and didn't have time to outline the work for Campbell.
      - Callaway Campbell, Cohuttah Springs, Murray County, Georgia to M[ildred] W[alker] Campbell,26 February 1859., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:110)
        Bought 640 acres of land in Georgia and has moved his slaves to it; has not sold the Toqua farm; is learning to farm.
      - N[athaniel] F[rancis] Cabell, Nelson County to Cha[rle]s Campbell, Petersburg, 28 February 1859., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 11:111)
        Encloses a copy of a letter of Col. Arthur Campbell.
      - Deposition of Mildred Walker Campbell before a Justice of the Peace, Petersburg, March 1859., 2 pages. (Box-folder 11:112)
        Affidavit as to the legal heirs of her Father Alexander Moore.
      - Hugh B. Grigsby, Norfolk, [Virginia] to [Charles Campbell], 2 March 1859., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:113)
        Has read his manuscript and corrected the punctuation; lists corrections to the manuscript.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg to Hugh B. Grigsby, 4 March 1859., 2 pages. Draft. AL. (Box-folder 11:114)
        Thanks him for reviewing his manuscript. Answers certain question raised about it.
      - Hugh B. Grigsby, Norfolk to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 6 March 1859., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:115)
        Suggests corrections to his manuscript.
      - Henry Howe, Cincinnati to Ch[arle]s Campbell, Petersburg, 8 March 1859., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:116)
        Advises him against having his new edition of the History published by himself. Advises him to accept an offer form a publisher who will assume all the risks.
      - P[hilip] Slaughter, Warrenton to [Charles Campbell], 15 March 1859., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 11:117)
        Randolph Lee has presented him with a copy of the History of Virginia. He has decided to edit a new edition of Hugh Jones' Present State of Virginia and asks Campbell's help.
      - D. S. Baldwin, [Richmond] to Charles Campbell, 16 March 18[59]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:118)
        Details of agreement between Baldwin, a literary agent and Campbell.
      - M[ary] B. Carter, Shirley to Mildred [W. Campbell],17 March 1859., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:119)
        Family news; thanks her for goods sent and received. A large party to be held at her house soon.
      - Anna C[ampbell], Petersburg, Virginia to Charles [Campbell], 24 March 1859., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:120)
        Brother William died; Charles Campbell in New York.
      - Lyman C. Draper, Madison, Wisconsin to Ch[arle]s Campbell, 25 March 1859., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 11:121)
        Sends him a copy of his school report, part of which will be published by Lippincott. Wisconsin has just established a town library system.
      - Hugh B. Grigsby, Norfolk to Townsend Ward, Philadelphia, 28 March 1859., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:122)
        Informs him that Campbell will be in Philadelphia soon, and asks him for assistance in getting the new edition of the History of Virginia published.
      - Charles Campbell, Philadelphia to "Dear Sir", 31 March 1859., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 11:123)
        Just concluded contract for his History of Virginia to be published by Lippincott and Co. of Philadelphia; wants this announced in the Express.
      - Townsend Ward, [?] to Charles Campbell, 31 March 1859., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 11:124)
        Would be glad if Charles Campbell could spend an evening with him.
      - Anna Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia to Charles [Campbell], 4 April 1859., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:125)
        Glad that he has made the arrangements with Lippincott and Co. in Philadelphia; hopes he will get his "nerves up" for the dental operation; school is going well.
      - Anna C[ampbell], Petersburg, Virginia to Charles [Campbell], 5 April 1859., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 11:126)
        Charles Campbell's book to be published soon.
      - Anna Campbell Petersburg, Virginia to "cousin", 7 April 1859., 3 pages. ACyS. (Box-folder 11:127)
        Brother William died; Charles Campbell in New York; had a short piece published.
      - C[harles] C[ampbell], Petersburg to Lyman C. Draper, [Madison, Wisconsin], 14 April 1859., 2 pages. Draft. AL. (Box-folder 11:128)
        Is sorry he has been diverted from his historical research, but feels his work in education to be equally valuable. Lippincott is going to publish a new edition of the History of Virginia.
      - Charlotte Wickham Lee, Arlington to Mildred [Campbell?],29 April 1859., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:129)
        Thanks her for gift.
      - Hugh B. Grigsby, Norfolk to C[harles] Campbell, 13 May 1859., 1 page. AS. (Box-folder 11:130)
        Has made some notes and corrections in the section on slavery in the History. Suggests omission of the statement that emancipation is desirable and expresses his own negative views of emancipation.
      - Cal[laway] Campbell, Cohuttah Springs, Murray County, Georgia to Harrison and Co., 15 May 1859., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:131)
      - D.S. Baldwin, Richmond to Charles Campbell, 24 May 1859., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 11:132)
        Baldwin requested an advance of Campbell's fee for handling subscription lists.
      - Edmund Ruffin, Marlbourne to [Charles Campbell], 15 June 1859., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:133)
        Ruffin proposed a second edition of a book of history. Asked Campbell for advice about publishers and terms of sale.
      - Ja[me]s E. Heath, Richmond to Charles Campbell, 17 June 1859., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 11:134)
        His "fracture" of two years ago still confines him to the "invalid's chair" and he writes with difficulty. Is glad that a new edition of the History of Virginia is coming out.
      - E[lizabeth] B[land] Stovin, Airley, Fauquier County, Virginia to Cha[rle]s Campbell, 8 July 1859., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:135)
        Wants to have Richard Bland remembered for his contributions; hopes Charles Campbell will help; hopes St. George Tucker and John Randolph Tucker will write about Theodorick Bland.
      - Lavinia M[oore] Alsbrook, New York City to "Aunt" [Mildred W. Campbell], 12 July 1859., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:136)
        Took a trip to New York and Northeast.
      - M[ary] B. C[arter], Shirley to Mildred [W. Campbell],29 July 1859., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:137)
        She has been on a trip to visit her family. Family news: Landonia is very sick.
      - C[harles] C[ampbell], Petersburg, Virginia to Anna [Campbell],[Trenton], 1 August 1859., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:138)
        Is sorting papers, pasting letters in a book; is correcting proofs; his book almost finished.
      - Sam[ue]l D. Campbell, Geneva, Coffe, County, Alabama to "cousin", 2 August 1859., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:139)
        Asks about controversy with Sparks; hopes his second edition will go as far as the death of Washington; will vote soon on whether West Florida will be annexed to Alabama.
      - C[harles] C[ampbell], Petersburg, Virginia to Anna [Campbell], 8 August 1859., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:140)
        Charles Campbell's mother is taking care of his children; death of Dr. James W. Alexander; is indexing his History of Virginia; local news.
      - Anna Campbell, Trenton to Charles [Campbell], 3 August 1859., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:141)
        Children well; misses her dead brother; will not get estates proceeds soon; could order her teeth for $5.
      - Hugh B. Grigsby, Charlotte Court House to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 13 August 1859., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:142)
        Acknowledges receipt of proofs of the History of Virginia. Is making slow progress with his own writing.
      - Callaway Campbell, Cohuttah Springs, Murray County, Georgia to Grandma [Mildred Walker Campbell], 14 August 1859., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:143)
        Farm going well.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg to Hugh B. Grigsby, 16 August 1859., 2 pages. Draft. AL. (Box-folder 11:144)
        Will forward the rest of the proof sheets when they arrive. Is glad to hear he is working again. Suggests change in the state's licensing law which, he says, puts authors at the mercy of publishers.
      - M[ildred] W. Campbell, Fauquier to Charles [Campbell], 16 August 1859., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 11:145)
        News of his children, who are all healthy Letter received from Anna in Trenton, who will soon return.
      - C[harles] C[ampbell], Petersburg, [Virginia] to Anna [Campbell],20 August 1859., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:146)
        Local news; has sent back the last proof sheet for his book and is working on the index; it is 751 pages.
      - Mildred W. Campbell to Charles [Campbell], 22 August 1859., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:147)
        News of his children, who are all well. Wheat crop is good.
      - C[harles] C[ampbell], Petersburg, Virginia to Anna [Campbell],2 September 1859., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:148)
        Family news; was elected Principal of Anderson Seminary; asks her advice whether to accept; difficulties with Board of Trustees.
      - Anna Campbell, Riverdale to Charles [Campbell], 4 September 1859., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:149)
        Fanny has whooping cough; her sore mouth better.
      - Anna Campbell, Riverdale to Charles [Campbell], 6 September 1859., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:150)
        Charles Campbell has been elected Principal; wants to ask Mother to live with them.
      - Tho[ma]s H. Wynne, Richmond to Charles Campbell, [Petersburg], 11 September 1859., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:151)
        Will make every effort to find his and his mother's missing baggage. Will soon tell him of his trip to New York. Hopes the new edition of the History will be a success.
      - M[ary] B. C[arter], Shirley to [Mildred W. Campbell], 22 September 1859., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:152)
        Hopes she will come to visit, and bring Alexander Campbell's two sons with her. Transmits news of a friend in Iowa, dying of consumption. Glad to hear that Charles Campbell has joined the church.
      - M[ary] B. Carter, Shirley to M[ildred] W. Campbell, Petersburg, 17 November 1859., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:153)
        Sends her sheets and towels to him for her. Also sends a lounge and some chairs to be repaired.
      - M[ary] B. C[arter] to [Mildred W. Campbell], [Late November (after-l9) 1859]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:154)
        Thanks her for doing work for her; encloses $5.
      - Mary F[airfax] Keller,[Alabama] to Sister [Mildred Campbell], 6 December 1859., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 11:155)
        Taking care of many children; Mr. Bagby has not yet succeeded with the claim; family news.
      - T[homas] H. Wynne, Richmond to Charles Campbell, [Petersburg], 21 December 1859., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 11:156)
        Sends two books for him to look at leisure.
      - James Woodhouse and Co., Richmond to Charles Campbell, 19 December 1859., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 11:157)
        Saw notice that Charles Campbell's History of Virginia almost ready. In the fire of October 1 in their building, they lost the list of subscribers, but will insert notice when book is ready. Requests 50 copies.
      - James Woodhouse and Co., Richmond to Charles Campbell, 23 December 1859., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 11:158)
        Received letter from Lippincotts that they will provide copies of History of Virginia. Charles Campbell need not send any copies.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg to James Woodhouse, 23 December 1859., 1 page. ADf. (Box-folder 11:159)
        Address order for History of Virginia to Lippincott and Co., the publishers, who have the subscription list. Told them that James Woodhouse would be good for sale of 100 copies.
  - Letters, 1860-1869., 259 items. (Box 12-14)
    - Letters, 1860., 58 items. (Box-folder 12:1-58)
      - Nanny K. S. Campbell to Charly [Charles Campbell], [c. 1860]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 12:1)
        Saw Barnum's museum.
      - [Charles Campbell] to Cally [Callaway Campbell], [c. 1860]., 1 page. AL. (Box-folder 12:2)
        Sent him the new edition of History of Virginia; is living at Anderson Seminary; Anna debilitated by nursing Fanny, who should be weaned.
      - Thom. H. Wynne to [?], 1860[?]., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 12:3)
        A listing of persons to whom Wynne sold copies of History of Virginia[The price of History of Virginia indicated a reference to second edition of that work, which was published in 1860].
      - T[homas] H. Wynne, Richmond to [Charles Campbell, Petersburg], 5 January 1860., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 12:4)
        There will be a delay in the receipt of a box of books from Philadelphia, from Lippincott.
      - J. D. Ghiselin, Jr., Norfolk to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 11 January 1860., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 12:5)
        Ghiselin dissatisfied with terms of sale of History of Virginia set by Lippincott and Co. 25% discount vs. 33% discount.
      - James Woodhouse and Co., Richmond to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 11 January 1869., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 12:6)
        Received two boxes addressed to Charles Campbell. Assume are copies of History of Virginia sent by Lippincotts. Should they be opened and books removed? Paid charges of $8.25. Agree price should be $3.00, but $2.50 for subscribers.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to James Woodhouse and Co., 13 January 1860., 2 pages. ADfS. (Box-folder 12:7)
        Two boxes by James Woodhouse contain 169 copies of History of Virginia; give them to Mr. Baldwin or Mr. Wynne. Lippincotts has shipped boxes with James Woodhouse's copies, if haven't come, take out what need and replace when they arrive. Price is to be $3.00, $2.50 to subscribers.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to D. S. Baldwin, 13 January 1860., 2 pages. ADfS. (Box-folder 12:8)
        Mr. Woodhouse has received copies of History of Virginia. Will attend to the delivery. Bills already made out. Price is $2.50 to subscribers. Mr. Teller may deduct his 5%, D. S. Baldwin his 20%.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to J. D. Ghiselin, Jr., [Norfolk], 14 January 1860., 2 pages. ADfS. (Box-folder 12:9)
        Discussed terms of compensation, which Ghiselin, a literary agent, was to receive. History of Virginia not written for profit, but to serve "our time honored Virginia."
      - T[homas] H. Wynne, Richmond to Charles Campbell, [Petersburg], 18 January 1860., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 12:10)
        Lippincott has sent him two boxes of the new edition of the History of Virginia, destined for subscribers. Thinks Campbell may have to issue another edition to pay expenses of this one.
      - James Woodhouse and Co., Richmond to Charles Campbell, 21 January 1860., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 12:11)
        Saw that Lippincotts was selling History of Virginia at $2.50. This settled the matter. Wished Charles Campbell had arranged to sell it at $3.00, but is too late now. The list of subscribers Charles Campbell sent is not half what they had obtained.
      - T[homas] H. Wynne, Richmond to Cha[rle]s Campbell, [Petersburg], 21 January 1860., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 12:12)
        Acknowledges receipt of personal copy of History of Virginia. Is about to embark on sale of it to his subscribers.
      - Hugh B. Grigsby, Norfolk to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 24 January 1860., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 12:13)
        Thanks him for new copy of the History of Virginia. Promises a very favorable review of it in the Richmond Enquirer.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg to Wyndham Robertson, 25 January 1860., 3 pages. ADf. (Box-folder 12:14)
        The letter questions the wisdom of a Virginia tax on books produced and sold in Virginia. Campbell felt the tax stifled the circulation of books, particularly locally produced books on Virginia topics.
      - T[homas] H. Wynne, Richmond to C[harles] Campbell, [Petersburg], 26 January 1860., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 12:15)
        Will try to boost sales of History. Reminds him to come to Richmond on Friday.
      - Sarah Jane Johnson, Petersburg, Virginia to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 27 January 1860., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 12:16)
        Student writes to teacher; enjoys school.
      - T[homas] H. Wynne, Richmond to Charles Campbell, [Petersburg], 30 January 1860., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 12:17)
        Sends a copy of today's Index, which contains a review of the History. Thanks him for mentioning his name in the History.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to John Esten Cooke, [Richmond], 2 February 1860., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 12:18)
        Forwards him a copy of the History of Virginia, and thanks him for his favorable review of it in the Index.
      - T. W. Imboden, Staunton to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 4 February 1860., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 12:19)
        Subscription agent requested payment authorization for his labors.
      - Callaway Campbell, Cohuttah Springs, Murray County, Georgia to "Grandma" [Mildred Walker Campbell], 5 February 1860., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 12:20)
        Is going to build a house; will not try to court [Lavinia Henley] again; has not sold his Toqua farm.
      - Charles Deane, Boston to Cha[rle]s Campbell, 11 February 1860., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 12:21)
        Have seen Charles Campbell's new ed. of his History of Virginia; has procured it for his Historical Society. Sends copy of Wingfield's Narrative, which Deane has recently had printed. Deane owns most of the works of Smith and others to which he refers.
      - Hill Carter, Shirley to Charles Campbell, 11 February 1860., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 12:22)
        Carter sent payment for 10 copies of Campbell's History of Virginia, plus mentioned four other purchases of the book.
      - Hugh B. Grigsby, Norfolk to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 15 February 1860., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 12:23)
        Has sent his review of the History to the Richmond Enquirer. Note in Charles Campbell's hand: "Answered Feb'y. 17th."
      - T[homas] H. Wynne, Richmond to C[harles] Campbell, [Petersburg], 15 February 1860., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 12:24)
        His agent is now selling the new edition of the History, but is having some difficulty.
      - Mary B. C[arter], Shirley to Anna [B.] Campbell,17 February 1860., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 12:25)
        Confusion over debts owed to Charles Campbell. Hopes his History will succeed.
      - John R. Kelby, Suffolk to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 21 February 1860., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 12:26)
        Had already purchased History of Virginia in bookstore.
      - Wm. B. Harrison to Charles Campbell, 22 February 1860., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 12:27)
        Sent payment for 2 copies of History of Virginia.
      - Hugh B. Grigsby, Norfolk to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 22 February 1860., ALS. 1 page. (Box-folder 12:28)
        His review of the History has appeared, with some unfortunate typographical errors.
      - T[homas] H. Wynne, Richmond to C[harles] Campbell, [Petersburg], 24 February 1860., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 12:29)
        Sends a copy of a paper entitled The Treason of [Charles] Lee, asking him to read and evaluate it. Will send money from sales of the History next week.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg to Hugh B. Grigsby, 25 February 1860., 1 page. AL. (Box-folder 12:30)
        Thanks him for the favorable review of the History of Virginia in the Richmond Enquirer.
      - Callaway Campbell, Cohuttah Springs, Murray County, Georgia to "Grandma" [Mildred Walker Campbell], 26 February 1860., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 12:31)
        Does not want to return to Virginia "my boyhood I look upon as a horrid dream"; likes Georgia; will not resume the courtship, "I am no longer held spellbound."
      - B. [B.] Minor, Fredericksburg to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 26 February 1860., 6 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 12:32)
        Pleased Charles Campbell included biographies of figures in History of Virginia. Might have given some help, gives examples; refers to Robert "King Carter, William Gooch, Thomas Fairfax, William Fairfax, Peter Leheup, John Carter." Sends information for Charles Campbell to use in next edition; B. B. Minor only wishes to defend Robert Carter's reputation. Corruption and confusion in every community. Also mention Gov. Benedict Leonard Calvert, Rev. Fontaine.
      - Robert Murray, Suffolk to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 29 February 1860., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 12:33)
        Subscription business and a request that Campbell transact a business matter for Murray.
      - W[illiam] J. Harris, Nottoway to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 4 March 1860., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 12:34)
        Sent purchase price for a copy of History of Virginia. Had been delayed in Richmond at Opposition Convention.
      - William[?] Brodman to Charles Campbell, 5 March 1860., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 12:35)
        Business arrangements about History of Virginia.
      - P. C. Sinding, Philadelphia to Charles Campbell, [Petersburg], 6 March 1860., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 12:36)
        Offered to act on Campbell's behalf as intermediary with Lippincott publishers.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg to John Minor, 7 March 1860., 2 pages. ADf. (Box-folder 12:37)
        Acknowledges a complimentary letter received from Minor about Campbell's recent book [ 2nd ed. of History of Virginia]. Campbell offers his opinion on scholarly technique (unfavorable) and classical historians (favorable).
      - T[homas] H. W[ynne], Richmond to Cha[rle]s Campbell, [Petersburg], 7 March 1860., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 12:38)
        Asks for Campbell's understanding of the contract between himself and Mr. Baldwin on selling his books.
      - L. Bremiss [?], John Rowlyn Newohand [?], Sam Osgood, Geo[rge] Folson, Geo[rge] Henry Moore, New York to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 9 March 1860., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 12:39)
        Invites Charles Campbell to a Washington Irving birthday celebration.
      - A. A. Gocke [?], Evergreen to [Charles Campbell], 10 March 1860., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 12:40)
        Acknowledged receipt of a copy of History of Virginia.
      - E. Ruffin, Jr., Beechwood to [Charles Campbell], [Petersburg], 19 March 1860., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 12:41)
        Sent price of seven copies of History of Virginia.
      - T[homas] H. Wynne, Richmond to C[harles] Campbell, [Petersburg], 20 March 1860., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 12:42)
        Encloses receipt for money paid Mr. Baldwin for selling his books. He still has seven copies of the book.
      - W[illiam] O. Newson, Camp 4th Alabama Vol[unteers] to Charles [Campbell], 7 April [c. 1860]., 2 pages. (Box-folder 12:43)
        Asks him to keep some blankets.
      - P. C. Sinding, Philadelphia to Charles Campbell, [Petersburg], 9 April 1860., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 12:44)
        An exceedingly flattering letter about History of Virginia. Sinding talked to Lippincott & Co., about Campbell's book. Proposed a sale of History of Virginia in Copenhagen, Denmark.